■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：跌跌不爱吃青椒  阿蘅阿蘅  猫中之王  醉芝士
校对：孤单南半球赛太公  孤单北半球YY猫   总监   YY猫
后期：孤帆     时间轴：加森
老爸老妈浪漫史
第九季  第十九集
2024年
谢谢你带我来这里
Thank you for bringing me here.
幸好我们及时赶到
I am so glad we made it.
暴风雪越下越大了
That snowstorm was getting really bad.
你觉得这就算暴风雪了吗
Wait, you think this is a snowstorm?
这不算什么  我告诉你什么是真正的暴风雪
This is nothing. I'll tell you about a snowstorm.
大一那年的寒假
It was winter break, freshman year of college...
马修和我是室友  但是我们
Marshall and I were roommates, but we weren't
-还不是好朋友  -等一下  打住
- really good friends yet. - Wait, stop.
这个故事你已经说过了
You've told me this one before.
说过了吗  什么时候
I have? When?
我想想啊
Uh, let's see. It was...
-整天听你说  -真的吗
- All the time. - Really?
你和马修开车回学校
You and Marshall drove back to school...
第2季第17集
一路单曲循环《五百英里》
"500 Miles" played on a loop.
你们选了一条小路  后来汽油没了
You took a back road, ran out of gas,
你们被困在暴风雪中  相拥取暖
got stuck in a snowstorm, spooned to stay warm--
至少你故事里是这么说的
at least that's your story--
最后你们成为了好朋友
and at the end of it, you were best friends.
好吧  没关系  不过你知道吗
Okay. Okay, that's fine, because guess what.
那还不算最严重的暴风雪
That wasn't even the worst snowstorm ever.
最严重的那年是2008年
It was 2008...
-巴尼和我  -当了一晚酒吧主人
- Barney and I... - Took over the bar,
遇见了亚利桑那州理工大学的行军乐队
met the Arizona Tech marching band--
"加油  母鸡队"
"Go Hens!"--
第4季第13集
马修去机场接莉莉的时候
And they played "Auld Lang Syne" when Marshall
他们还演奏了《友谊地久天长》
picked up Lily at the airport.
好吧
Okay.
我有跟你说过马修那次...
Have I told you about the time that Marshall...
想在莉莉祖父的房子上挂圣诞彩灯
tried to put Christmas lights on Lily's grandparents' house
第7季第12集
后来隔壁的熊孩子
And the little ragamuffin from next door
害他被困在房顶上了
left him stranded on the roof?
-莉莉告诉你的吗  -对
- Did Lily tell you that one? - Yeah.
"熊孩子"这词是莉莉说的
Lily used the word "ragamuffin."
看来我的故事都跟你说过了
So I've told you all my stories.
恐怕是  不过幸运的是
I'm afraid so. But luckily,
我还有大把你没听过的故事
I have plenty of stories that you don't know yet.
比如我和大学的室友
Like the one where my college roommates and I
跑去脱衣舞男吧
went to this male strip club...
你们的朋友"老二鼻"被一根老二
And your friend Dongnose got smacked on the nose
打到了鼻子
with a dong?
我听过了
I know that one.
好吧
Okay.
那说过为什么"老二鼻"叫...
What about the story that explains how...
"老二鼻"这个绰号吗
Dongnose got her nickname "Dongnose"
而且那与被老二扇到鼻子的事件完全没有关系吗
and that it had nothing to do with the dong-smacking incident?
听过了  很喜欢
Heard it, loved it,
我把它称为21世纪最精彩的巧合
called it the greatest coincidence of the 21st century.
我所有的故事你都听过了
You know every one of my stories.
我所有的故事你也听过了
And you know every one of mine.
这就正式说明
I guess it's official.
我们是老夫老妻了
We're an old married couple.
-太好了  -我们做到了
- Nice! - We did it!
这不是莫斯比夫妇嘛
Well, well, if it isn't the Mosbys.
来这里享受一个远离孩子们的浪漫周末
Here for a romantic weekend away from the kids.
幸好你们房间两边都没有住人
it's a good thing there's no guests on either side of you,
因为床垫的弹簧会像奶酪工厂的老鼠一样
'cause those bedsprings are gonna squeak like mice
吱吱叫个不停  对吧
in a cheese factory. Am I right?
千万别像你的朋友
Just don't break any of the lamps
巴尼和罗宾那样搞到打碎台灯  好吗
like your friends Barney and Robin, okay?
-其实事实并非如此  -当然不是
- That's not how the lamp broke. - Of course not.
好了  你们玩开心
All right, you have fun, you two.
什么台灯
What lamp is this?
婚礼那天罗宾打碎的台灯
The lamp Robin broke the day of the wedding.
天啊  这个故事你没听过
Oh, my god. You don't know this one.
我的老天
Oh, man.
这可是个好故事
This is a good one.
我是指什么刺激情节都有
I mean, it's got everything.
阴谋  背叛  台灯
Intrigue, betrayal, lamps.
这可是个跌宕起伏的故事  请系好安全带
It is a ripping yarn, so buckle your seatbelt.
-快讲故事  -好吧
- Just Tell the story. - Okay.
故事是这样的
Here goes.
罗宾打碎了一个台灯
Robin broke a lamp.
够了  不许玩了
Okay, this has to stop.
别啊  我们正玩得起劲呢
Come on, we're just having fun.
这是个漫长的周末
It has been a long weekend.
这是我放松的方式
This is how I relax.
是吗
Really?
这是你放松的方式吗
This is how you relax?
整个早上一个球都没进过吗
By not getting a single shot past me the entire morning?
你真逊  特布罗斯基  你打球像个老太太一样
You suck, Scherbatsky, you shoot like my grandma.
特布罗斯基  老虎的屁股你也敢摸
Okay, Scherbatsky, you just poked the dragon.
等着  新娘要发力了
Here comes the bride.
好了好了  不如我们
Okay, okay. How about we switch to an activity
换个更适合今天要
that's more suited to somebody who's,
结婚的人的活动  好吗
you know, getting married today?
我们要去喝一杯吗
We gonna go chug some Labatts?
不如我们喝一杯回忆的美酒吧
I was thinking we could chug some memories instead.
"巴尼和罗宾
"Barney & Robin:
永生永世的爱人
Lovers forever and ever and ever:
爱情故事"
a love story."
听起来好俗气
Sounds cheesy.
我永生永世都要吐了
I'm gonna go barf forever and ever and ever.
再见啦  姐儿们
See you, hosers.
哪里俗气了
It's not cheesy.
瞧
See?
能告诉我住在九号房的客人是谁吗
Uh, can you tell me the name of the guest staying in room nine?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
这有违酒店的隐私政策
That would violate hotel privacy policy.
或许我的老朋友林肯先生
Well, maybe my old friend Mr. Lincoln...
五元钱上印的头像是林肯
能让你透露下信息
can emancipate that information.
抱歉  我没说清楚
I'm so sorry, I wasn't clear.
我不能违反酒店的隐私政策
I can't violate our hotel privacy policy.
就为了5美元
For five dollars.
上面有数字2的就可以了
Something with a two on it is fine.
这是少有的20美元  我是走运才能搞到这张呢
But those are super rare and the one I have is kind of lucky.
痛快点  莫斯比先生
Just give me a 20, Mr. Mosby.
那个房间住的是西衫・川上女士
That room belongs to a Ms. Susan Tupp.
我的老天
Oh, boy.
天啊  你太漂亮了
God, you're gorgeous.
我等不及要[穿]上你了
Oh, I can't wait to be inside you.
巴尼  快出来  今天可是你结婚的日子
Barney. Get out here, this is your wedding day.
-她在哪里  -谁
- Where is she? - Who?
我刚花了一大笔钱打听到
Look, I just grossly overpaid for some information
这个房间的住客  所以肯定是正确的
about this room, so I know it's accurate.
那个房间住的是西衫・川上
This room belongs to Susan Tupp.
谁
Who?
西衫・川上
Susan Tupp.
-谁  -西...
- Who? - Sue...
川上
Tupp.
-穿上西装  -我不正努力着吗
- Suit up. - I'm trying to.
我要你帮我挑一件
I need you to help me pick the suit
走结婚红毯时穿的西装
I'm gonna wear when I walk down the aisle.
要走红毯的是罗宾  你只需在尽头等着
Okay, Robin walks down the aisle, you wait at the end of it.
好吧  那就挑一身大家都站起来
Okay, then the suit I'll be wearing
迎接我进礼堂时穿的西装
when they all stand as I enter the chapel.
-那也是她  -是吗
- That's also her. - Really?
老天  男同胞在婚礼中
Man, the fellas sure do get boned
-真是一点地位都没有啊  -好了
- on the whole wedding thing, don't they? - Okay.
我们好好帮你挑一件吧
All right, well, let's, let's pick you a suit.
你最中意的是哪几件
What are... What are the top contenders?
经过仔细的考量
Well, after careful consideration,
我把选择目标缩小到了
I have narrowed it down to
这一排...
these ones...
和这一排...
and these ones...
以及这房间里所有剩下的
and the other ones in this room
和隔壁房间里的所有的西服
and all the ones in the adjoining room.
所以你把范围缩小到你所有的西装上了
So you've narrowed it down to all your suits.
没错  我们死定了
Yeah, we're screwed.
这张照片是你和巴尼
And this is a picture of the restaurant
在第一次约会的餐厅
where you and Barney had your first date.
现在你俩都要结婚了
And now you're getting married.
这张是你和巴尼
And this is the receipt from the meal
第一次约会时的用餐收据
you and Barney ate at that restaurant on your first date.
现在你俩都要结婚了
And now you're getting married.
我们待会儿再看好吗
Can we look at this later?
待会  哪里还有待会
Later? There is no later.
罗宾  今天这日子一生只有一次
Robin, this is a day you only get to do once.
你应该马上认识到它的重要性
You need to appreciate the importance of it right now.
我的天
Oh, my God.
我怎么到现在才意识到
How did I only just now realize this?
姐们儿  这家旅馆的点播台
Dude, this hotel has the Wedding Bride 2
有《新娘快跑》第二集呢
on pay-per-view.
《新娘快跑》第二集之蜜月迷情  售价14.99
中大奖啦
Score.
这真是我人生中最开心的一天呀
This is the best day of my life!
我知道罗宾不是特别女性化的女人
I mean, I know Robin's not the girliest girl,
可原以为到了结婚的那一天
but you'd think on her wedding day,
她至少会有点多愁善感吧
she'd be at least a little sentimental.
每个人处理婚礼的方式都不一样
Everyone deals with getting married differently.
我理了一个我认为是史上最难看的头发
I got what I thought was the worst haircut ever.
直到我帮自己修剪出了真正最难看的头发
Till I fixed it with the actual worst haircut ever.
所以我们才有了史上最难看的婚礼照片
Which led to the worst wedding photos ever.
但至少你结婚那天有被吓昏头
But at least you had a wedding day freak-out.
宝贝  不要担心
Baby, Don't worry.
用不了多久  罗宾就会被
Any minute now, Robin's gonna get smacked in the face
"天啊  今天我结婚"的事吓得惊慌失措
with her own "holy crap, this is my wedding" moment,
她绝对会吓得上蹿下跳  我保证
and then she's gonna wedding out all over the place. I promise.
可这事不能着急  必须顺其自然
But you can't force it, it has to just happen.
她一看到点播台有《新娘快跑》第二集
Mm, I don't know. I mean, she bailed on my scrapbook
就把我的剪贴簿丢到一边去了
when she found out the Wedding Bride 2 Is on pay-per-view.
点播台有《新娘快跑》第二集吗
The wedding bride 2 is on pay-per-view?!
打扰一下
I'm sorry, did...
你们是不是在聊《新娘快跑》
Did I hear you guys talking about the Wedding Bride?
-又来了  -你们是在说电影还是
- Oh, God. - The movie or the...
轰动一时的百老汇歌舞剧
smash broadway musical?
轰动  现在一部只上演了
Smash? Oh, oh, oh, I-I guess a show's a smash now
96周的戏也可以算轰动了  是吧
if it closes after only 96 weeks.
《新娘快跑》是我老公的
So my husband's ex-fiance's husband
前女友的老公写的剧本
wrote the screenplay for the wedding bride.
"杰德・莫斯理"就是以泰德为原型的
"Jed Mosley" was based on Ted.
杰德的原型不是我
Okay, Jed was not based on me...
那可不是玩具  熊孩子
That is not a toy, you ragamuffin.
那是我在文艺复兴大会上赢的货真价实的流星锤
That is an authentic flail I won at the renaissance fair.
不完全是
...Entirely.
但不管怎样
But, regardless, there's...
我心里还是有挥之不去的伤痛
there's still some lingering pain there and...
你大概也可以理解
well, as you can imagine,
我的朋友们都答应我永远不会看这电影
my friends promised me that they'd never watch it.
他们真是够义气
Those are some good friends.
他们是最棒的
Oh, they're the best.
我的小弟弟
My wiener!
真不敢相信杰德要我们发誓不看这电影
I can't believe Jed made us promise not to watch this.
等等  你是想说泰德吧
Wait, you mean Ted.
无所谓了  都是同一个人
Whatever. Same guy.
我还以为你会有一套为了婚礼
See, I would have expected you to have an extra-special suit
特意找裁缝做的西服
tailor-made just for this occasion.
我有啊
Oh, I did.
蒂姆・古恩  《天桥霓裳》顾问
我的兄弟蒂姆・古帮我做了一套完美的西装
I had my boy Timmy G make the perfect wedding suit.
你听说过"量身定做"吗
You ever heard of "bespoke"?
这件西装简直是"百里挑一  美轮美奂"
This suit was be-freaking-screamed.
可我今早试穿的时候
But then I tried it on this morning
那西服特别不舒服  又痒又不合身
and it was uncomfortable and itchy and completely wrong.
就像是专门给体形难看
It was like a suit made for someone with terrible posture,
没品钱少的人做的
no taste and limited funds.
来  给你吧
Here, you take it.
剩下的问题就是
The only question is,
其他件西装里我该挑哪一件呢
which of these other suits do I pick?
好衣服太多  难以抉择啊
There are so many great ones to choose from.
这一件怎么样
Uh, how about this one?
很好  很好  就这件了
Yes. Yes, that's the one.
问一下  我曾经穿着它上了一个马术女小丑
Oh, hey, quick question: Is it weird to get married in a suit
现在再穿着它结婚  会不会很奇怪
that you may have worn while banging a female rodeo clown?
我知道你在想什么
I know what you're wondering.
没错  上面的头发和下面的"头发"颜色一样
Yes, the carpet matched the drapes.
当然很奇怪  每一个细节都很奇怪
Of course that's weird. Every part of that is weird.
那么  这一件怎么样
Uh, what about this suit? Huh?
我曾经在这件西装里"塞了不少小兔子"
Let's just say I stuffed a lot of bunnies in that suit.
巴尼  你非得说得这么淫秽吗
Ugh, Barney, do you have to phrase it that way?
是真的小兔子  泰德  这是我的魔术服
Actual bunnies, Ted. This is my magic suit.
你的思想不要那么龌龊好吗
Get your mind out of the gutter.
不过  我的确穿着它参加过花花公子的派对
Though, I did once wear it to the playboy holiday party and, uh...
我曾经穿这件西装"塞"了不少"兔女郎"呢
Let's just say I stuffed a lot of bunnies in that suit.
-那这一件呢  -天啊
- How about this one? - Oh, man,
我穿着它和一个"伴游"玩得可疯狂了
I went crazy on an escort in that one.
巴尼  够了
Barney, come on.
是福特的伴游车  泰德我是在车上搞的
A Ford Escort, Ted, I did it on a car.
和一个我可能付了钱可能没付钱的伴游妹
With a woman who I then may or may not have paid.
所以这一件也不行
Yeah, that one's out, too.
你的婚礼几小时后就要开始了
Okay, so your wedding's in a few hours.
现在还在看这么糟糕的电影
Kind of strange to spend those hours
有点太奇怪了吧
watching a terrible movie, right?
糟糕  莉莉  这电影简直是意外的惊喜
Terrible? Lily, this movie is a revelation.
真不敢相信泰德一直不准我们看呢
I can't believe that Ted wouldn't let us see it.
是啊  他为什么对这部电影这么不满
Yeah. Why was he hanging so much beef on this movie?
就因为有个角色的原型是他吗
Just 'cause there's a character based on him?
对了  我要让所有婚礼都违法
Of course. I'll make all weddings illegal.
这样斯黛拉就永远当不成新娘了
Then Stella can never be a wedding bride.
不行就是不行  小宝贝
No-can-I-do's-ville, baby doll.
我想说  "放轻松  泰德
It's like, "relax, Ted,
没什么大不了  你应该感到荣幸好吗"
It's no big deal. You should be flattered."
现在我要拿出珍藏已久的巧克力蛋糕
And now to celebrate with that piece of chocolate cake
来庆祝一下啦
I've been saving.
什么  谁吃了我的蛋糕
What?! Who ate my cake?!
什么蛋糕
Uh, what cake?
奶修
Narshall!
Narshall?
奶修  好大的胆子啊
Narshall. How dare they?
那简直是又无礼又荒谬
That is insulting and ridiculous
我跟那个角色根本不一样
and I am nothing like that character.
我要起诉与参与这部电影的所有有关人员
I'm gonna sue everyone involved with this film.
所以你起诉他们的理由是
So, you're-you're gonna sue them on the grounds that
那块蛋糕般的事情从未发生过吗
nothing like that cake thing has ever happened?
要是泰德不希望我吃那块蛋糕
If Ted didn't want me to eat that cake,
就应该在上面写张卡片
he should have put a note on it.
-外婆好  -罗宾  亲爱的
- Oh, hi, grandma. - Robin, sweetheart.
我想把这个给你
I wanted you to have this.
是我和你外公结婚时的照片
It's me and your grandpa on our wedding day.
好窝心啊
Aw, that's so sweet.
看到我的捧花了吗
See my bouquet?
这些野花...
Those wildflowers--
本应该是绣球花的
They were supposed to be hydrangeas,
但是花店那边出了点状况
but there was a mix-up at the florist's.
我当时好生气
I was so upset.
你外公就去教堂后面
Your grandpa went behind the church
摘了这些野花给我
and picked those wildflowers for me.
-而现在他被埋在了...  -同家教堂后面
- And now he's buried... - Behind the very same church,
他的坟墓被同样的野花环绕着
surrounded by the very same wildflowers.
外婆  我们在看电影  先这样啦
Okay, grandma, watching a movie. Got to go.
每个假期  我外婆都给我讲这个烂故事
Every single holiday, that same dumb story.
抱歉外婆  这故事没你想得那么感人
Sorry, grandma, not as touching as you think it is.
就在同家教堂后面吗
At the very same church.
现在我们来看看
Now, I want to see
杰德能否从那个保温瓶里拿出那根香肠
if Jed can get his wiener unstuck from that thermos.
不行就是不行  小宝贝
No-can-do's-ville, baby doll.
不好意思  请问你这是
Uh, I'm sorry. Did you just
在婚礼当天不让新娘好好看电影吗
turn off the bride's tv on her wedding day?
是吗  今天你结婚啊
Oh! Oh! Is this your wedding day?
抱歉  完全看不出来
I'm sorry. I couldn't tell
你表现得好像今天就是一个普通的周日
because you're acting like it's any other Sunday morning,
但其实不是
and it's not.
莉莉  如果你一直在等着
Lily, if you're waiting for me to suddenly turn
我会变成待嫁小女子 你还是放弃吧
into th-th-the wedding bride, you just give up.
-我就不是那种人  -好吧
- That's just not me. - Fine.
也许我们都应该不把这场婚礼当回事
Maybe we should all just act like this wedding's no big deal.
我甚至都不想穿上那套伴娘礼服
Maybe I don't even feel like wearing my bridesmaid's dress.
很好  不就是一场婚礼吗
Great. It-it's just a wedding.
没有人会在意穿着
Who cares what people wear?
-就穿这件吧  -对不起  我做不到
- Say yes to the suit! - I can't! I can't.
太好了  因为我刚好准备了另一套裙子
Great. Because I actually brought a different dress
-正想试试看呢  -好啊
- that I'd like to wear. - Fine.
不是吧
Oh, no.
不如我现在就去换上吧
Maybe I'll go put it on right now.
-去吧  -怎么了
- Go right ahead. - What?
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
什么  怎么了
What, why?
-这个故事我也听过  -真的吗
- I know this story, too. - Really?
对  罗宾和莉莉大吵了一架
Yeah. Robin and Lily get in a big fight
几分钟后  有人敲门
and then, a few minutes later, there's a knock at the door.
你好啊
Hello.
-我以前给你讲过这个  -讲过几次吧
- I've told you this one before. - A few times.
我现在就是
I'm just...
一个总是讲老掉牙故事的无聊老男人
a boring old man who won't stop spinning yarns.
别这么说  我很喜欢听你的故事
Oh, hey. I love your yarns.
我很希望你一直这样讲下去
I hope you never stop spinning them.
但是...
But...
你是我一生挚爱  泰德熊
You're the love of my life, pooh bear.
我只是担心你
I just worry about you.
我不希望你变成一个活在过去里的人
I don't want you to be the guy who lives in his stories.
人生只能向前走  不能回头
Life only moves forward.
那后来怎么样了
So what happens next?
我是说莉莉和婚纱的事
With Lily and the wedding dress, I mean.
是这样  她带了那套裙子
Well... She brought the dress
是为了和马修重新拍几张婚纱照
so that she and Marshall could get new wedding photos taken.
因为在我听过的另一个故事里...
Because in yet another story that I know...
不要啊
No!
要不是这些故事占了这么多空间
What kind of space would I have in my brain
我的脑子里能放多少东西啊
for other things if I didn't know all this?
算了  说不定也就记点无聊的东西
Eh, probably just state birds or some crap.
莉莉想借用一下罗宾的摄影师
So, uh, Lily wanted to borrow Robin's photographer.
应该没什么问题
That shouldn't be a problem.
没什么问题  罗宾
Shouldn't be A problem, Robin?
这当然有问题
Of course it should be a problem.
今天是你的婚礼啊
This is your wedding.
你不能让别人借用你的摄影师
You can't let somebody borrow your photographer.
别担心  她是开玩笑的  罗宾
Don't worry. She's not serious, Robin.
当时我们婚礼时那套西装  我没带着
I didn't even bring the suit that I wore to our wedding.
你带了  在房间里放着呢
Yes, you did. It's in our room.
去穿上  我们一定要拍
Go put it on. We're doing this.
罗宾  既然你不介意的话
And, Robin, since you don't seem to care,
那我就穿着这套婚纱去参加婚礼啦
I think I'll be wearing this to the ceremony.
-好  -好
- Fine! - Fine!
好
Fine.
这问题有很简单的解决方法
There's a very simple solution here.
我们面对现实吧
We might as well just face it.
海军陆战队结婚时必须穿军服  所以...
U.S. Marines have to get married in uniform, so...
我要去参军了
I'll just go enlist.
兄弟
Dude,
我们可以一起参军  那是我们的梦想
we can enlist together! That's the dream!
-这算什么梦想  -不知道能不能自己选室友
- That's not the... - I wonder if they let you pick bunkmates.
但愿可以吧
I hope they do.
虽然我可能会要单间房  你会交到朋友的
Although I might want to request a single. You'll make friends.
真是够了
Look, enough of this.
蒂姆给你做了这么棒的西服
Tim made you this amazing suit.
穿上
Put it on.
感觉好奇怪
This feels weird.
因为是新西服
That's because it's new.
从来没被人穿过的西服
It's a suit that's never been worn before,
你甚至做梦都没想到会穿上它
A suit you never dreamed you'd wear.
与这套西服有关的记忆还没有发生
All of this suit's memories are still ahead of it.
你想象一下
Look, picture it, huh?
婚礼现场
The ceremony.
-众人为我起立吗  -是为新娘起立
- When everyone stands up for me? - They do that for her.
应该的
They should.
她会犹如仙女下凡
She's gonna look amazing.
当然是这样
You'd better believe it.
她走向圣坛
She walks down the aisle,
你们说出婚誓
you say your vows,
然后去婚宴
you go to the reception,
跳起婚后第一支舞
you have your first dance.
在不知不觉间  就像魔法一样
And before you know it, just like magic,
你发现
you realize...
这是最完美的选择
It's a perfect fit.
你说得对  泰德
You're right, Ted.
就是它[她]了
This is the one.
谢谢
Thanks.
那么
So...
皮带
Belts.
莉莉  好漂亮的婚纱
Hey, Lil. Nice dress.
你俩真是天生一对
you two were made for each other.
难道没人在乎我穿着婚纱吗
Like, does no one care that I'm wearing this dress?
我在乎
I care.
好了  没事了
Okay. Now you're good.
听着
Okay, look,
我知道今天是你们的大喜之日
I know this is your wedding, but this is
但今天对我们来说都很重要
a big moment for all of us.
这也许是我们所有人最后一次相聚
This may be the last time we're all hanging out together
下次再见谁知道是什么时候
for who knows how long.
明天一早
I mean, tomorrow morning,
泰德就要去芝加...
Ted's leaving for Chicag...
-糟糕  -莉莉
- Oh, boy. - Lily.
慢着  你已经知道了
Wait, you already know.
你已经知道了
You already know.
你娶了莉莉  这意味着
You're married to Lily, which means...
你告诉她时  她就用口袋做掩护发短信给我了
She pocket-texted me while you were telling her.
那么
So...
大家都知道  我明天要搬去芝加哥
Everybody knows I'm moving to Chicago tomorrow.
莉莉是对的
Lily's right.
我们不知道下次何时再聚
We don't know the next time that we'll all be together.
然后我想大家都意识到
And then I think it hit all of us.
我们不知道下次何时再聚
We didn't know the next time we'd be together.
就是这样了
This was it.
很好笑
And it's funny.
在那样的时刻
In a moment like that,
要面对的事情太过情绪化时
when what's really happening is too intense to deal with,
有时候最好就是
sometimes it's best...
一切尽在不言中
To leave it unspoken
把握最后相聚的快乐时刻
and just enjoy each other's company instead.
我一直想看这部电影
You know, I've been wanting to see this movie.
太棒了  电影时间到
Yes, movie time.
新娘在婚礼前
So it's not bad luck for the...
看到新郎的礼服  会不会带来噩运啊
bride to see the groom in his wedding suit?
不会的
No, I think it's fine.
-好帅气的领带  -谢谢
- Nice tie. - Thanks.
我差点就选了一条浅蓝色的
There was a cornflower blue one I almost went with.
那会让你的眼睛更漂亮
That would've brought out your eyes.
你不止带了一条领带对吗
You brought more than one tie, right?
我想尽量少带点行李嘛
I was trying to pack light.
这样吧  也许
Hey, you know what, maybe the,
伴郎团应该去吃点东西
uh, groomsmen should go get some food.
我不想让泰德忍受这部电影
I don't want Ted to have to sit through this movie.
太感谢了  奶修
I appreciate that, Narshall.
你不是吧  该死的
Really? Aw, damn it.
抱歉  我在飞机上看了
Sorry, I saw it on a plane.
这么说现在这个成槽点了吗
What, so this is gonna be, like, a thing now?
就是槽点了  奶修  对吗
Yeah, It's gonna be a thing now, Narshall. Right?
-奶修  -哥们
- Narshall. - Dude,
淡定  斯瓦尼
settle down, Swarley.
没错  斯瓦尼・西伦  放轻松
Yeah. Yeah, Swarlize Theron, take it easy.
我今天结婚  给点面子好吗
Man, this was supposed to be my special day.
我们熬过暴风雪了
Hey, we survived the storm!
奶修  是你干的好事吗
Oh, Narshall, did you do that?
不  不是我
Nope. Wasn't me.
那是谁啊
Well, then who was it?
大猩猩  大猩猩
A gorilla! Gorilla!
泰德真碰到这种事了吗
So that really happened to Ted?
这是真事
That is exactly what went down.
证据确凿
Chapter and verse.
-没有冰块了  -我去拿
- Out of ice. - I'll get it.
不用  我去  你坐
Oh, no. Got it. Sit down.
而且自动贩卖机投币口松了
Plus, the, uh, vending machine's got a loose coil.
我要去用屁股猛撞几下
I'm gonna try to hip check my way
弄些免费的彩虹糖
into some free tropical skittles.
你姐姐和大多数新娘不同  对吗
Your sister's not like most brides, is she?
她是特布罗斯基家的人  才不会因为结婚
She's a Scherbatsky. She's not gonna lose her timbits
timbit是著名的加式点心
就大乱阵脚惊慌失措呢
just 'cause she's getting married.
我想有些人就是不可能拥有
I guess some people just never have that
"哎呀妈呀  我要结婚了"这种时刻
"Holy crap, this is my wedding" moment.
妈
Mom?
故事就是这样
That's the story.
有一个意外的结局
Right down to the surprise ending.
这真的是意外吗
Is that really such a surprise?
得了吧
I mean, come on.
她当然会去
Yeah, of course she showed up.
什么样的母亲会错过女儿的婚礼
What mother is gonna miss her daughter's wedding?
别  别这样
No. Come on.
没事  没关系  我很好
It's okay. I'm fine. I'm okay.
巴尼真的穿着潜水服进了酒吧吗
Did Barney really wear a scuba suit into the bar?
这个故事我跟你讲过无数遍了
I've told you that story a million times.
但巴尼从哪里弄到的潜水服
Yeah, but where did Barney get the scuba suit?
他偷的
He stole it.
什么
What?
是的
Yeah.
真不敢相信我忘了
I can't believe I forgot that.
他走进体育用品店
He... Walked right into a sporting goods store,
试穿了潜水服  大摇大摆地从大门走了
tried on a scuba suit, and walked right out the door.
走了20条街回到家
Walked all the way home in it, like, 20 blocks.
穿着潜水服的人
Guy in a scuba suit,
走在百老汇大街上
just walking down Broadway.
他应该坐牢
He should be in prison.
对  他坐牢的原因可多了
Well, yeah, for lots of reasons.
-我们中最会偷东西的是莉莉  -不是吧
- You know, the thief of the group is Lily. - No.
-我的天  莉莉  -"她偷了我的心"那种
Yes. Oh, my god. Lily... No. She stole my heart.
不  我告诉你  莉莉
No, n-no, I'm telling you, Lily,
比方说...
from like, uh...
鲍勃・迪伦 《若你遇见她 代我问声好》
若你遇见她  代我问声好 *
* If you see her say hello
她可能在丹吉尔港 *
* She might be in Tangier
去年早春伊人离去 *
* She left here last early spring
我听说她住在那里 *
* Is livin' there, I hear
告诉她  我很好 *
* Say for me that I'm all right
虽然日子过得有些迷惘 *
* Though things get kind of slow
她可能以为我已将她遗忘 *
* She might think that I've forgotten her
别告诉她  她依然在我的心坎上 *
* Don't tell her it isn't so.